If we're going to get Matilda out of here,
Chosen Squad, 7 Hours Before Carrying Out Their Plan
this port is the only way to do it.
Yeah, that's a good call.
There's a freighter leaving at 11 PM,
and we're going to sneak her in amongst its cargo.
Same Time ~ Klaus and Lily Arrive
We'll create a diversion to distract the soldiers
and make the dockworkers evacuate.
How's Annette looking?
Will she'll make it in time?
I think she'll be fine.
The Chosen Squad's Hotel
She'll have all the tools we need built by this evening.
Good...
MISSION: Forgetter IV
What the hell are you still doing here?
It reeks of blood in here.
Welter, I assume the fact that you're here in person
means that this is the work of a spy?
The weapon used was piano wire.
It was set up in a terrifyingly well-designed booby trap.
According to the local authorities,
the corpses were so mangled they couldn't
tell which pieces went with which bodies.
It's the exact same MO used by the
Imperial spies we're hunting.
That's odd...
There's a lingering scent of tear gas in the air.
This room's been attacked twice.
Someone filled it with tear gas three days ago,
and two days ago, the enemy spy carried out
their piano wire massacre.
Who were the victims?
I'm told they were a group of criminals
who mostly targeted tourists.
The punks stole passports and luggage
to reel in their victims.
Ah, that makes sense.
Hold it, Bonfire!
What did you figure out?
Nothing in particular.
Just that this case is too
complicated for me to handle.
Don't you lie to me!
You Foreign Intelligence Office bastards aren't the
only ones fighting to keep the Republic safe, you know.
There's something fishy going on in Modello.
I can sense a great evil here,
the kind that sends shivers down my spine.
A great evil?
Yeah, someone who wears a righteous smile and
manipulates the ignorant to serve their own ends.
There's someone like that here in the city,
someone so fundamentally evil that
their very existence is an abomination.
As the military, it's our job to put those people down.
Now, tell me everything you know.
I admire your sense of duty.
However, I have my own position to consider.
Stay out of my way.
You son of a...
Here's a warning for you.
Don't chase the spy into the sea.
They'll give you the slip.
We're putting the search for the others
on hold for the time being.
Say what?
The four of them are likely trying to
help Annette's relative escape.
Regardless of whether or not they're
making the right decision,
what we need to worry about is that spy's ally.
Wait, Teach, you already figured out what's going on?
Somehow or other, yes.
Welter and his army boys think the
Imperial spies are a team,
but they're wrong.
By my estimate, there's only one of them.
But while the lone spy is currently having
Thea and the others help them escape,
they've doubtless called for aid
from their motherland, too.
The girls probably haven't noticed,
but the Galgad Empire will have sent in a heavy hitter.
He looks like a mushroom!
A mushroom?
That's a hell of a way to
greet someone for the first time.
Are you my backup?
Thank goodness...
So, the Empire didn't abandon me after all!
Didn't they?
I could be just here to tie up a loose end.
You're a side trip for me.
The only reason I'm even here
in the country is because
it's where a man with the code name
Deepwater went missing.
I have full discretion to kill you
or let you go as I see fit.
You smell like blood.
You killed someone recently, didn't you?
That's not exactly best practices
when you're on an undercover op.
It's true that I was in big trouble.
Those army shitstains had me surrounded,
my tools had been stolen, and I was at my wit's end.
But then, a miracle happened!
Lo and behold,
I ran into my long-lost daughter,
who'd become a spy for the Republic!
So, what, you had a touching reunion?
Good for you.
I used that to hit her.
I hit her and hit her and beat all
the memories out of her,
and left her there black and blue.
And now, she and her friends are helping me escape.
You should hear how lovingly she calls me "Mom"!
She has no idea that I'm just taking advantage of her!
What a stupid, foolish little girl she is!
I knew you were a sicko,
but at least get rid of that death stink.
You smell so bad,
anyone who knows what they're doing
could sniff you out in a heartbeat.
Oh, pardon me.
I killed them for revenge,
or rather, I just really wanted to.
Well, do what you will.
I'm gonna do my thing,
then head back to the Empire.
Tell me...
Do you have any maternal love for her at all?
Not even a smidge.
I mean, the kid's a creep.
Um, is this really going to work?
I don't know about this whole
hiding in the cargo business...
Up until recently, it  wouldn't have.
Not with wooden crates and barrels.
They're too small for a person to comfortably fit inside,
but container shipping has started
to catch on in Din lately,
and people can slip inside those like it's nothing.
It's opened up new options for spies.
The ship we're putting you on
isn't going to the Empire,
it's headed to the Lylat Kingdom.
They'll be keeping a closer eye on
the ships headed for Galgad.
We'll help you get out of the country,
but you'll have to figure out how to get
from Lylat to the Empire on your own.
I can do that.
Annette made this for you.
You can use it to burn through the
shipping container's lock from the inside.
It won't let you down, yo!
Thank you.
How are things looking out there, Monika?
Monika?
Oh, right.
The cargo just came in,
and I was able to get a visual on our container.
It's a blue shipping container with the number 3-896.
Annette...
On it!
Bombs away, yo!
What's that?!
Is that a fire?
Get the dockworkers to safety!
Hurry, hurry!
That's step one finished.
Next up, we gotta draw the soldiers away,
but that'll be tricky.
I think that's Captain Welter Barth.
I take it he's quite the catch?
Keep it in your pants.
Rumor has it he's one of the army's
best and brightest.
And with how well he's commanding his men,
I believe it.
Still, we can't afford to back out now.
Hold on!
We're being sniped?
By who?!
And from where?
I don't think we should go out right now.
I've got a really, really nasty feeling about this.
She dodged it?
How?
Daughter... Republican spy...
A group of teenage girls...
It can't be.
Is it the same ones?
Well, I can kill one of 'em
and see how things play out.
You noticed me.
Looks like I reeled in a bigger catch than expected.
The only people who would react like that
to seeing my face are Imperial spies.
Between that and the superhuman
sniper skills you just showed off...
Are you with Serpent?
I've sealed off the stairs.
Is that foam poisonous?
Teach...
FUUUUUCK!
Why should I have to fight...
this absolute monster?!
All you're doing is fleeing?
With skills like yours, surely you could be doing more.
Say what you like, buddy!
I'm doing things my way!
The danger vanished?
Well, that's convenient.
Let's hurry.
Me wo aketa kikkake wa
There's no way we'll be able to break their line head-on.
Here, I'll carry your stuff.
Kokoro saku joukei
Oh, thank you.
I didn't realize it was gonna be this good.
Leave this bit to me.
Hirari hirari yubi no sukima kara
Annette,
Mietekuru shinjitsu wo nirame
give me every bomb and smokescreen you've got.
Kizukareta no wa, rakuen?
What's going on?!
Massakasama ochite
Aa tatoe kouya demo
Fire! Don't let the spy get away!
Hitori de ikiru to oritachimashou
Back when they fought,
Klaus parried Corpse's bullet with his knife.
Ikanakucha
I wonder if I could do that?
Koko ni aru hana wa ima eien nare to
Angle... Distance... Speed... Timing...
Gokujou no chihedo wo haite watashi ga ueta mono
I should be glad there are no rebounds to worry about.
Kono koe de ashi de te de watashi no mama mogaku hodo ni
Doushiyou mo nai sekai ga itoshii
Oh, that was easy.
Tadoritsuku wa kanarazu
Don't get rattled! Surround them!
I'm over here, folks!
I'm not gonna kill you,
Musekaeru hodo no yume
but that doesn't mean I can't have some fun.
Monika, everything feels so much easier,
now that you're back on my side!
Let's split up and look for that shipping container.
If you find 3-896, let us know over the radio.
Behind you!
Don't worry.
He's with me.
No wonder I didn't smell any misfortune.
I'll give you big reward later,
so could you tell me your current
deployment formation?
O-of course!
I'm gonna go look over here.
I'll look over there.
In that case, I had better go too.
Hold on.
Sorry if this is just me imagining things...
What is it?
Matilda, were you...
Were you about to kill that soldier?
I could feel your bloodlust.
What's going on?
If you're just a smuggler,
then why did that come so readily to you?
You're too late.
It's far too late in the game to
start asking questions like that.
It's unreal how slow you are on the uptake.
You liar!
Thea, honey, you're a nobody.
You're soft, and it made manipulating you
so incredibly effortless.
In all my life, I've never met anyone whose goodwill
was as easy to take advantage of as yours.
I'm joking!
I really am grateful to you,
and I really do love my daughter.
That wasn't bloodlust, I was just a little surprised.
Sorry, but as someone who's been doing this
spy thing for a bit longer than you,
I wanted to tease you a little.
You wouldn't gun me down
over a little joke, would you?
Not when your teammate calls me "Mom" so lovingly.
I found the shipping container, yo.
Do you read me?
Over.
Shall we be off, Thea?
Stay back, you monster!
If you take one step closer,
I'll use this to blast a civilian away!
That hardly qualifies as a serious threat.
You're not going to hit anyone firing blind like that.
I mean, I've never actually tried it.
But I'm pretty sure I'd hit.
Also, I planted a bomb in that hotel over there.
In five minutes, it's gonna blow.
You're bluffing.
I'm pretty sure you can tell I'm not.
And you're not willing to sacrifice a single one of the
citizens Inferno loved and protected, are you?
That's your weakness.
Sorry, but I know every bit of intel
there is to know about you.
That mentor of yours spilled the beans
when he turned traitor.
Answer me.
Why did he betray his homeland?
Who knows?
Now, you'd better hurry up and get going.
Otherwise, you might not make it in time, Bonfire.
Deepwater, that is, Roland,
probably fought you and lost,
but I don't fight people head-to-head,
and that's why I don't lose.
It's the best option I have available to me.
I've memorized your face.
I'll finish you off next time we meet, Mushroom Man.
Please don't call me that.
I'd rather you used White Spider.
This is where we part ways.
Thank you all so much.
Annette, I'll give you 30 seconds.
For what?
To say your goodbyes.
Go ahead and make them as heartfelt as you can.
Right! I forgot!
Here's your toolbox back.
Do you want to come? With me?
I refuse, yo.
I like being with the these guys.
Okay.
Then, you don't have to return my toolbox.
You can have it.
Really?
In that case, I'll give you mine as a present!
There, swapsies!
They're the exact same.
Ah, so you built this one.
Yup! It's a matching set with yours, Mom.
Goodbye.
Goodbye, yo.
Sis!
Thanks for helping make my wish come true!
Well, there's no use dwelling on it.
All along, my primary objective
was to protect that smile.
Wow, he really did set a bomb.
In case someone like me came after him, yes.
I can't believe someone actually
managed to escape from Teach.
This should be the spot.
I warned Welter not to chase the spy into the sea
in the hope that his pride would
force him to do exactly that.
And if he did...
Oh hey, Klaus.
Haven't seen you in a while.
M-Monika?!
What are you-
You stink!
Magnificent.
MISSION: Forgetter IV
Come onnnnn!
You can't do stuff like this, Erna!
You went missing and didn't even call?!
I was worried sick!
That was pretty rude of you, Klaus.
You coulda told me we had
someone like her on our team.
I was all worried over nothing.
You let me go around making a fool of myself
saying that the team lacked ruthlessness.
I've made it far enough that I'm probably safe.
I wonder if the abusive old hag made it out okay?
Besides, she isn't even my real daughter.
She's just a baby I found dumped
in the trash at a train station.
I only took her in because I figured
she would be useful for my spy work.
I did feel a little bad
when her eye got crushed during the plastic surgery
to make her look like we were related.
But that girl's very existence is an abomination.
As she got bigger, she started turning into
something too terrifying to comprehend.
She scared me so bad I hit her over and over,
and luckily, it knocked out her memories
so I could abandon her.
But thinking back now,
I realize that when you have a defective model,
you have to make sure to dispose of it properly.
I'll give this to her to remember her mother by.
I rigged up the inside with a bomb.
I'll play the doting mother through to the very end,
then blow my daughter to smithereens.
Klaus! Bro!
I'd better flee!
Caught you.
This little game of tag is over.
I've finally been caught, yo!
How was it?
Did you enjoy your vacation?
It was super fulfilling!
I learned loads.
I didn't get why the others were making
such a big deal about moms at first.
But now, I've become one part smarter!
Do elaborate.
She gets mad at me sometimes,
she praises me sometimes,
and she supports me in what I want to do.
That's what a mom is!
So when Mom gets all sad, I get all mad.
That's what she means to me!
And this mom of yours, is it Matilda,
the woman you reunited with?
Nope! It's Thea!
That woman isn't fit to be my mom.
The day after we discovered she was a spy,
I figured out what kind of person she really was.
When we met up at the beach,
she smelled like blood.
I was furious, yo!
She butts in out of nowhere,
and when we get her toolbox back out of
the goodness of our hearts,
she goes and uses it to kill people!
It was like she was throwing
Thea's goodwill back in her face!
Who does that?!
But you didn't choose to hand her over to the military.
An Imperial spy used the tools we retrieved
for her to murder Republican citizens.
If those army jerks found out,
it would be a big scandal for Lamplight.
In other words, it made for a messy situation.
If Matilda got caught by the army,
they would get blackmail material on us.
You were running up against your time limit.
And most importantly, your blood was boiling.
That's why you decided to assassinate her.
By pretending to help her escape,
you were able to seal her
within a shipping container.
Bingo! Good going, Bro!
You changed the number, didn't you?
Probably with a water-soluble paint.
That way, you were able to get her into the container
with Thea and the others none the wiser.
Later, the paint washed off in the rain
and revealed the true digits.
Wow, back-to-back bingos!
That container's being loaded onto a ship
headed for another continent.
Is there any chance she escapes?
I set up the burner I gave her
to break down almost immediately.
She's doomed, yo!
So, Matilda will spend her ten-day,
cross-continental voyage
confined to her container, and starve to death.
That's what she gets for making me mad, yo!
Are you sure you went far enough?
Matilda might call for help
when she realizes what's happened,
and there's a non-zero chance that
someone outside the container hears her.
That was my kind little act of mercy.
I left her with a one percent change of surviving!
And now, that one percent is gone, too!
She made the bomb herself.
She's the one who planted it,
and she's the one who set it off.
You swapped it out with something identical?
Yup!
What a pathetic woman,
getting hoisted on her own petard.
If she hadn't tried to blow me up,
Aa, kataashi de tatte tsurai okimochi
she might have lived!
Mou kyouyuu shite chanto yottemasuka?
Are you gonna call me an abomination, Bro?
Ai o motte chigau nanika abiserare
What do you mean?
Did someone call you that?
They...
Yakkaisou de jama na watashi, waita waita
Huh?
Someone so fundamentally evil
their very existence is an abomination.
Honto daijoubu?
That's not it.
Sore kiite dou suru no?
Ruthless as they were, Annette's decisions
led the Republic to the best possible outcome.
Tada homeru dake de ii
Klaus? Bro?
Iienai ienai kagami no sei
Do you know what "Forgetter" means, Annette?
Mirenai kienai yogoreta sei
Please, tell me.
When someone forgets themselves, it refers to a state
Assari kamikitte sameta me de uso o minuku
where nothing else enters their field of view.
Katenai kaenai na muku na hin
They forget everything except themselves,
and once they've devoted everything they have
Suteru mono nai mukurodashi
to fulfilling the urges welling up in them,
Kakugo wa kakusazu hada de te ni motte aragau
all that remains is pure ego.
It's the ultimate act of pure selfishness.
(whoo, whoo, ooh)
Rakugaki darake no aimai na unmei
Annette, that ruthlessness you have is a weapon
that you and only you possess on the team.
(whoo, whoo, ooh)
Kami de sae keisotsu ni damashiteku
There's nothing abominable about it.
It's magnificent.
I'm very proud of you.
This is why I love ya, Bro!
In return, I'll tell you a special secret.
There's another reason why I killed Matilda, yo!
What's that?
"She hasn't changed a bit."
We hadn't seen each other in four years,
and that horrible thing is what she said to me!
Even killing her wasn't enough to quell my rage!
I know I'm not getting taller, and it sucks, yo.
If your actions were the result of you
holding true to your beliefs,
then you should be proud of them.
Tell me, Teach.
What can I do to make this frustration go away?
For that,
perhaps it would be better if I gave you the
boss's answer rather than my own.
Ms. Hearth's?
That's right.
That one probably suits you better.
"Make sure you take the next mission
and absolutely nail it."
That's all there is to it.
Classic Ms. Hearth...
What a wonderful answer.